<?xml version="1.0" ?>

<lotte_stekeleburg_config home_image = "images/home_image.jpg">

<font color="#000099"><a href=" " target="_blank"> </a></font>

<agenda>

<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">The Insect Cookbook</header>
	<image>images/17-04-12.jpg</image>
	<description><p>Very exciting to contribute with my photography to the first Dutch book about cooking with insects!</p><p>It contains interviews, recipes to try at home (!) and interesting background information on politics, world food security and environmental issues.</p><p>I portrayed all the people that were interviewed; politicians, top chefs, insect rearing companies and food designers. To gain the best result, it's my working method to join the interview to get to know the person and the subject. With such an interesting subject I didn't mind spending this "extra" time at all.</p><p>Order the book <a href="http://www.uitgeverijatlas.nl/result_titel.asp?Id=3401" target="_blank">here</a> or look at my photographs in the category "Commissioned" in the portfolio called "The Insect Cookbook".</p><p>And of course I got the change to eat some insects.
Now you!</p></description>
	<filters color="category-1" date="17.04.12" year="recent"/>
	</item>

<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">Dynamic People</header>
	<image>images/26-01-12.jpg</image>
	<description><p>Looking back at 2011 I realize that I have photographed more people then ever before. Two years ago it was still a wish to create more portraits in commission... Now it is almost becoming my core business!</p><p>Besides making single portraits I lately photograph a lot of people in the context of their activities. Gardening is one of my favourites! Besides (or due to this) this change of subject, last year I developed a more dynamic style.</p><p>Time to update my portfolio!</p></description>
	<filters color="category-2" date="26.01.12" year="recent"/>
	</item>


<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">Urban Gardening</header>
	<image>images/31-08-11.jpg</image>
	<description><p>Since last spring Caroline Zeevat supervises an urban gardening project in Schiebroek-Zuid for the housing corporation <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.vestia.nl/RotterdamNoord/Actueel/Nieuws/Pages/StadslandbouwproduceertinSchiebroek-Zuid.aspx" target="_blank">Vestia</a></font>. Her approach is to provide basic conditions for the wishes and plans of people living in the neighborhood. With success!</p><p>The removal of wild bushes served as a launch to make space for some new private gardens in between the flats. Since that moment the number of gardens is growing as fast as the enthusiasm of the locals! The inner garden of some senior apartments has been enriched with a glass house. Besides that a communal garden has been created in which children help their parents to grow flowers, fruit, vegetables and herbs. Many visit the lively garden before they start cooking.</p><p>I photographed the process from the early start. Look at the colorful images of this beautiful project in the portfolio "Schiebroek-Zuid" in the category "Commissioned" or visit the <font color="#000099"><a href="http://stadslandbouwschiebroek.blogspot.com" target="_blank">weblog</a></font> of the project!</p></description>
	<filters color="category-1" date="31.08.11" year="recent"/>
	</item>




<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">Co-parent Book</header>
	<image>images/20-04-11.jpg</image>
	<description><p>Today the book <font color="#000099"><a href="http://degroteco-ouderwebsite.nl/" target="_blank">"Het Grote Co-ouder Doe Boek"</a></font> by Petra Vollinga is finished and presented in Amsterdam. A positive and practical book about co-parenting full with tips for divorced parents, but also for the children being involved.<br/><br/><font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.knalrood.nl" target="_blank">Studio Knalrood</a></font> did the design for this colourful book and asked me to photograph nine people that were interviewed to share their co-parenting experiences in the book. For me it was very inspiring to meet and portrait nine persons at nine different locations with the task to create a positive and consistent series of photographs.</p><p>You can see the series in the portfolio "co-parent book" in the category "Commissioned", but you should also go and see the great final result in the bookstore. If you are a co-parent yourself the advice is to buy two copies of the book -together with your ex!- for the best result.</p></description>
	<filters color="category-1" date="20.04.11" year="recent"/>
	</item>

<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">Peanut Butter        E-Card</header>
	<image>images/06-03-11.jpg</image>
	<description><p>
<font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.boijmans.nl/nl/7/kalender/calendaritem/783/de-pindakaasvloer-van-wim-t-schippers" target="_blank">Museum Boijmans van Beuningen</a></font> has acquired the "Peanut-Butter Platform". This conceptual work by Wim T. Schippers can be installed at any size with any brand of peanut butter.</p><p>The museum asked me to photograph the floor sculpture of 4 by 12 meters together with the artist. One of the photos I made is used for the official invitation card. You can also send it as an e-card from the website of the museum using <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.boijmans.nl/nl/203/e-cards/ecardimage/39" target="_blank">this</a></font> link.</p><p>The "Peanut Butter Platform" will be exhibited in the museum from March 5 to a date yet uncertain, depending on the sustainability of the floor sculpture...</p></description>
	<filters color="category-1" date="06.03.11" year="recent"/>
	</item>




<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">On Weeds</header>
	<image>images/28-01-11.jpg</image>
	<description><p>I am the owner of a small garden with a little summerhouse just outside the city center of Rotterdam. One of my garden neighbours is author and graphic designer Caroline Zeevat. We met last spring, when she had just started a book about weeds and was looking for a photographer. Being interested in everything related to gardening and still struggling with my own weeds I decided to join her and garden designer <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.plantaardig.nu" target="_blank">Suze Peters</a></font> in creating this book together.</p><p>It feels like a nice paradox; suddenly to be looking for weeds instead of trying to get rid of them. Not very difficult since weeds have the quality of being everywhere! In the meantime I have photographed an enormous amount of plants -new specialisation!- and portrayed some very inspiring people.</p><p>The result will be a manual that helps you to recognise, destroy, but also enjoy weeds. Filled with stories, interviews, tips and recipes the book will put weeds into another light. Send me an email if you would like to receive a message once the book gets published!</p></description>
	<filters color="category-2" date="28.01.11" year="recent"/>
	</item>



<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">Site Specific Photo</header>
	<image>images/06-01-11.jpg</image>
	<description><p>A new year feels like a good moment to launch and explain a concept I have been working on: site-specific photographs, created on the very same place where they will be finally presented.  For example of a surprising scene happening in your own living room. Looking at the final piece of art in the same room will evoke the feeling: "did this really happen here?" Or a portrait of your family shot in the same setting where you will be showing the final photograph, causing an interesting Droste effect.</p><p>I have worked on this concept a couple of times for different galleries and private houses. Most recently I photographed a specific scene for design studio <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.13speciaal.nl" target="_blank">13 Speciaal</a></font>, showing the owners at work with two clients. Presenting the final image in the studio just above this same table creates the feeling of a mirror and makes you as a new client recognise the situation.</p><p>If you are interested in a tailor made site-specific piece of art of your own, let me know. Together we will get to amazing ideas!</p></description>
	<filters color="category-2" date="06.01.11" year="recent"/>
	</item>

<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">Book Launch</header>
	<image>images/27-10-10.jpg</image>
	<description><p>Artist <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.studioroosegaarde.nl" target="_blank">Daan Roosegaarde</a></font> creates interactive landscapes that respond intuitively to sound and motion. His first book Interactive Landscapes is designed by <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.paulswagerman.nl" target="_blank">Paul Swagerman</a></font> and offers a futuristic perspective on everyday reality and presents a complete overview of his work.</p><p>During the years I photographed all the projects of Studio Roosegaarde, like Dune, Liquid Space, Flow and Intimacy. This means the book also shows a lot of my work, including the cover and some wonderful spreads!</p><p>You can order a copy at the website of <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.naipublishers.nl/kunst/daan_roosegaarde.html" target="_blank">NAI Publishers</a></font>.</p></description>
	<filters color="category-3" date="27.10.10" year="before"/>
	</item>


<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">No New Notes</header>
	<image>images/14-10-10.jpg</image>
	<description><p>Some months without new notes can mean two complete different things. Nothing happened or too much happened. This summer it was due to the latter. I simply couldn't find time to write about it all. I'm not complaining, because I photographed some very interesting projects of some very good artists.</p><p>Last week for example I photographed the installation "Showcasing Today's Essentials" of <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.esmevalk.com/works/30-showcasing-todays-essentials" target="_blank">Esme Valk</a></font> in SMART Project Space in Amsterdam. You should take a look at her website to see the resulting photographs and also watch her movie "Asymmetry is Dynamic".</p><p>Some of the other things I was working on this summer will appear in the notes I'm planning to write as soon as possible...
</p></description>
	<filters color="category-1" date="14.10.10" year="before"/>
	</item>


<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">Joost Swarte Exhibition</header>
	<image>images/29-07-10.jpg</image>
	<description><p>The <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.architectuurhaarlem.nl/node/780" target="_blank">ABC Architectuurcentrum</a></font> in Haarlem shows work of the cartoonist <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.joostswarte.com/" target="_blank">Joost Swarte</a></font>, who was involved in the design of different architecture projects.</p><p>Joost Swarte collaborated with the architect <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.dollab.nl" target="_blank">Henk Doll</a></font> on the creation of a social housing project in Haarlem, called the Johannes Enschede Hof.</p><p>Some years ago I photographed the Johannes Enschede Hof in commission of the architect. For the current exhibition "Joost Swarte bouwt..." one of my photographs is used to show the project.</p><p>You can go and visit the exhibition in Haarlem until the 30th of August and you can also see my photos of the Johannes Enschede Hof on my own website in the portfolio "dollab" in the category "Commissioned".
</p></description>
	<filters color="category-1" date="29.07.10" year="before"/>
	</item>


<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">Portrait Published</header>
	<image>images/18-06-10.jpg</image>
	<description><p>Writer <font color="#000099"><a href="http://biancaboer.nl" target="_blank">Bianca Boer</a></font> published her first collection of poems. It is called <font color="#000099"><a href="http://ljveen.nl/result_titel.asp?Id=2898" target="_blank">"Vliegen en andere vogels"</a></font>. At the back of this publication you will find a portrait of Bianca with the skyline of Rotterdam in the background. It's made by me.</p><p>Just enjoy one of her poems in this note:</p><p>ik maak verliefdheid<br/>op de brug van je neus<br/>en prop de gaten vol rozenblad<br/>vers geplukt vochtig geurend<br/>je goddelijke mond geef ik lucht<br/>ademen doe je voor mij<br/>stikken via mij</p></description>
	<filters color="category-1" date="18.06.10" year="before"/>
	</item>

<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">Reflecting Objects</header>
	<image>images/22-05-10.jpg</image>
	<description><p>Some years ago I was helping a product photographer shooting cocktail drinks. I was fascinated by the time and effort it took to photograph reflecting objects. At the time I was convinced I would never do product photography myself. Being an assistant I sometimes showed up in test photographs and that's how I got the idea of creating a series on being an assistant in my own set.</p><p>Some months ago I got in contact with <font color="#000099"><a href="http://bold-design.org" target="_blank">Bold Design</a></font> and we started working on a concept to photograph their new vases. It ended up with real product photography!</p><p>Take a look at the series "assistant" in the portfolio "Self" and at the portfolio "bold design" in the portfolio "Commissioned", both on this website.</p><p>This weekend Bold Desing organised a special sale of Blown Shapes at their studio in Paris, with an exhibition of my photographs.
</p></description>
	<filters color="category-1" date="22.05.10" year="before"/>
	</item>

<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">Photo Story Weekly</header>
	<image>images/12-04-10.jpg</image>
	<description><p>Last year <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.viewbook.com" target="_blank">Viewbook.com</a></font> started the <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.viewbookphotostory.com" target="_blank"> PhotoStory Awards</a></font>; a contest for photographers to create stories with a linear series of photographs in an online gallery.</p><p>Because of great success it's continued with <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.photostoryweekly.com" target="_blank">PhotoStory Weekly</a></font>; a bi-weekly source that shows the stories behind the submissions from the contest.</p><p>PhotoStory Weekly invited me to be part of their editorial team. I wrote a text on a story that really caught my eye: "My White Night", by <font color="#000099"><a href="http://http://www.scarletthooft.com/" target="_blank">Scarlett Hooft Graafland</a></font>. A Dutch artist that travels to isolated parts of the world to give her artistic response to different cultures and landscapes, combining photography with performance and sculpture. Her surreal landscapes are not only an attraction to the eye, but also discuss important cultural subjects.</p><p>I invite you to take a look at "My White Night" and read my view on the story using the following <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.photostoryweekly.com/scarlett_hooft_graafland" target="_blank">link</a></font>.</p><p>On the right: "Lemonade Igloo" by Scarlett Hooft Graafland.</p></description>
	<filters color="category-6" date="12.04.10" year="before"/>
	</item>


<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">Flash Weekend</header>
	<image>images/04-03-10.jpg</image>
	<description><p>The newest digital cameras provide extreme good results at High ISO, so most of the time you don't need to use your flash anymore if you don't want to. Nevertheless you can create interesting light situations with flash or studio light.</p><p>To update and upgrade our knowlegde on lightning techniques, I spent a whole weekend inside the studio with colleagues and friends <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.erniebuts.nl" target="_blank">Ernie Buts</a></font> (photographer) and Floor van Slochteren (artist) to share our skills and have some great experiment.</p><p>We created several light situations, copied favourite photographers and studied important optical aspects to understand the behaviour of light and the character of shadow. It was a very instructive time with great result and good fun. Especially ingenious was our creation of the RGB-eye, which can be a great detailed surprise in every portrait!</p><p>On the right: results of our Flash Weekend.</p></description>
	<filters color="category-3" date="04.03.10" year="before"/>
	</item>
<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">Art, Property of Politics</header>
	<image>images/19-02-10.jpg</image>
	<description><p>
The artist <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.jonasstaal.nl" target="_blank">Jonas Staal</a></font> explores and discusses the relationship between art and politics. His essay <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.fondsbkvb.nl/nieuws/actueel/2009/11/5924_postpropaganda_essay.php" target="_blank">Post-Propaganda</a></font> was the motivation for the group exhibition "The People United Will Never Be Defeated" in <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.cbk.rotterdam.nl/tentrotterdam/index-uk.htm" target="_blank">Tent</a></font>. in which Staal shows an installation that brings together art works from the collections of the political parties represented in Rotterdam.</p><p>With Jonas Staal I visited the city council of Rotterdam to photograph the  art works as they are 'exhibited' within the party quarters. You can see the result in the free publication "Art, Property of Politics", with which Staal criticizes the dominating statement of all Dutch political parties that politics is not supposed to influence the 'content' of art. According to Staal, politics already shows a -democratic- ideological interest in the role of art in society, exactly by pointing out the political task to protect the 'freedom' and 'independency' of the arts.</p><p>You can see the photographs in the portfolio "jonas staal" in the category "Commissioned". With interest in the subject you should also read an essay by Jonas Staal in <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.jonasstaal.nl/Post-propaganda_Groene.pdf" target="_blank">De Groene Amsterdammer</a></font> and  <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.htvdeijsberg.nl/82-polemiek/" target="_blank">HTV the IJsberg</a></font> nr. 82.</p><p>On the right: the publication "Art, Property of Politics", designed by <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.evalindeman.com" target="_blank">Eva Lindeman</a></font>.
</p></description>
	<filters color="category-1" date="19.02.10" year="before"/>
	</item>


<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">Who is the Creator</header>
	<image>images/30-01-10.jpg</image>
	<description><p>
When someone proudly shows me a beautiful image of architecture, I have difficulties how to react. Yes it's a very nice image, but who deserves the compliment: you or the architect? Teaching photography I discuss this matter with my students, because every start of the semester I get to see images of architecture, statues, fountains, arts, etc. I teach my students to not simply focus their cameras on the creations of others. I should include mushrooms in this context, a very popular subject amongst amateur photographers!</p><p>Last week I got confronted with this matter myself. At an exhibition of <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.germainekruip.com" target="_blank">Germaine Kruip</a></font> I photographed some beautiful light situations I wanted to add to my online portfolio "light sketches", but suddenly I got confused. Germaine Kruip shows installations in which the effect of light is part of her work. So maybe I was just documenting and not creating something of my own...</p><p>This subject is as difficult as the question "what is art?" We could discuss when a photographed subject is a piece of art by someone else and what a photographer should add to turn it into something creative by himself. Interesting, but comparable with the discussion spend so much time on to get photography into the world of arts. With success, but without clear answers.</p><p>Taking a close look at the oeuvre of Germaine Kruip, you'll discover that this question on art and reality is part of her work. I think it's not in line with the concepts of Germaine Kruip, but I decided that I don't want to show my images of 'her light' in my own portfolio. But I do like to show them here on the right!
</p></description>
	<filters color="category-5" date="30.01.10" year="before"/>
	</item>


<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">New Year Old Work</header>
	<image>images/10-01-10.jpg</image>
	<description><p>Maybe strange to start a new year with old work, but I'm glad to finally show this series I created in 2002 during my exchange period in Strasbourg. I started playing with the furniture in the room I rented for four months. The result shows an absurd atmosphere I still appreciate. After years I scanned the analogue films to be able to show this series on my website.</p><p>Some people ask me why I don't show the date of creation of my photographs on this website. To be honest it just wasn't part of the design, which is based on images as much as possible. Of course showing years is interesting to be able to see the development of an artist. On the other hand -by not showing- it might be easier to consider all the photographs on my website as a body of work I'm still proud of today. In a certain way it keeps me critical to what I show, because the year is no excuse.</p><p>Please take a look at "serie play" in the portfolio "Self"</p></description>
	<filters color="category-2" date="10.01.10" year="before"/>
	</item>


<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">Permanent Light Portfolio</header>
	<image>images/02-09-09.jpg</image>
	<description><p>I'm always having a small digital camera with me to make snapshots of my life. But I also use it to photograph things that inspire or attract me. After some years of carrying this camera with me, I can conclude that I especially seem to focus on interesting light situations.</p><p>In the process of creating and in visual result these images really differ from the more staged and conceptual photographs - mostly self-portraits - I made until now. First I thought it difficult to consider these new images being part of my body of work. That's why I created a separate online-presentation to show them, called "Light Portfolio" in May 2009.</p><p>Some months and various reactions later, I decided today to admit them on my website, so I created a new category called "More", where you will find the serie "light sketches". A new name for showing images that focus on light situations, but are also light in the other sense of the word; not heavy, just visual studies without a big concept.</p><p>Besides I changed the name of my "Art" portfolio into "Self", because it's hard to tell what art is anyway. This previous "Art" portfolio is exclusively showing self-portraits, so this seems a very clear solution at the moment. It all keeps on moving... I'm curious what my categories will be like in one year!</p><p>I invite you to view my "light sketsches" again, but now straight from the website. I will continue updating it with new results, so please keep coming back.</p></description>
	<filters color="category-2" date="22.12.09" year="before"/>
	</item>



<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">Dune Images</header>
	<image>images/29-11-09.jpg</image>
	<description><p>Alongside the river Maas a new public interactive artwork called Dune, created by <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.studioroosegaarde.nl" target="_blank">Studio Roosegaarde</a></font>, found its permanent place in Rotterdam. To attract people to come and visit, a special tram was travelling between the city centre and De Esch where it is located. The tram was designed by <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.paulswagerman.nl" target="_blank">Paul Swagerman</a></font> with the help of photographs I made for  Studio Roosegaarde.</p><p>Besides this spectacular publicity a magazine on Dune was presented at the day of the opening. A wonderful publication called Progressive Realities by Paul Swagerman and Adele Chong; filled with Dune's interactive evolution via images and articles. Because I photograph for Studio Roosegaarde for some years now, lots of the images used were created by me. Click <font color="#000099"><a href="http://issuu.com/paulswagerman/docs/progressive_realities_01" target="_blank">here</a></font> for a preview.

Photographs on the right by Paul Swagerman</p></description>
	<filters color="category-1" date="29.11.09" year="before"/>
	</item>

<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">Perform and Document</header>
	<image>images/27-10-09.jpg</image>
	<description><p>Last weekend I got reminded of the topic of my thesis Master Photographic Studies: "The Photo Document of a Performance". When I finished my research I didn't have the connections to publish the text. After this theoretical study I decided to focus on my photography practice again, so I haven't been working on the subject ever since.</p><p><font color="#000099"><a href="http://performanceartevent.nl" target="_blank">PAE</a></font> (Performance Art Event) organized a Saturday in Rotterdam full with performances in <font color="#000099"><a href="http://wolfart.nl" target="_blank">Wolfart</a></font>, but started already on Friday with an information evening in <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.tentrotterdam.nl" target="_blank">TENT</a></font>. Part of the programme was a lecture on "The Documentation of Performance Art" by Marjolein Schaap, dealing with the same questions as my own research. Is the documentation able to translate the concept and impact of a performance? Do you damage essential medium specific qualities of the performance -like being unique and unable to collect- if you decide to document it? What happens with the medium if you start selling the document as an artifact?</p><p>The discussion panel also tried to answer other interesting questions -like the need of a performance platform- and that's why there wasn't enough time to truly discuss the topics I'm personally interested in.</p><p>But the good thing is that I got exited on the subject again! My thesis is about the documentation of performances from the photographic point of view. If you are interested to read it, don't hesitate to send me an email and I will reply with a pdf-file!</p><p>Shown on the right: "Performance by Ben d'Armagnac", photographer Cathrien van Ommen, 1978
</p></description>
	<filters color="category-6" date="27.10.09" year="before"/>
	</item>

<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">The Self</header>
	<image>images/24-08-09.jpg</image>
	<description><p>The self-portrait is a topic that provides me with interesting questions every time I face one. For example why the artist decided to make it. To study his person, his face, autonomy in general, the material of the medium used or was it to show an emotion or maybe pure narcissism?</p><p>I have my own reasons to make self-portraits. I really enjoy the way of working; I don't need to ask anyone for help, can start anytime at the perfect moment and continue as long as I need. I love running between the camera and my frame. Besides that I think I'm a perfect model in the sense of being rather neutral to represent a person in general. And that's what my photography partly is about: showing subjects in a more universal setting to make it possible for the spectator to identify with the shown situation and create his own interpretation on the topic.</p><p>Although I'm almost in every picture, it's never about me! Besides this confusing contradiction, it starts to feel as a restriction in my body of work and that's why I think about quitting to photograph myself. I'm not sure whether I will succeed in this new challenging mission, but taking people their portraits seems a good start to practise.</p><p>Another question that fascinates me on the topic self-portrait is whether you can visually recognize one even if you don't know the face of the artist. I think I sometimes can when the piece of art shows a specific combination of a turned face, eyes showing a certain emotion and looking into the "camera". Impossible to formulate this exactly keeps the topic mysterious!</p><p>The reason why I wrote this note today is that I visited the exhibition <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.noordbrabantsmuseum.nl/arachna/nl/42/met_eigen_ogen" target="_blank">Met Eigen Ogen</a></font> in Den Bosch. Besides that I got triggered by the exhibition of <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.boijmans.nl/nl/7/kalender/calendaritem/116" target="_blank">Charley Toorop</a></font> some months ago in Boijmans and I have some very nice books on the topic at home. One of my favorites is "66 Zelfportretten van Nederlandse Fotografen". And I love the photographic self-portraits of the painter Magritte!</p><p>Shown on the right: "De schaduw en zijn schaduw", Renee and Georgette Magritte, 1932
</p></description>
	<filters color="category-5" date="24.08.09" year="before"/>
	</item>

<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">Popular Portrait</header>
	<image>images/21-04-09.jpg</image>
	<description><p>Some months ago I became extra interested in portrait photography.  I collected photos of people and questioned myself what made them into good or bad portraits. And what does a photo need to call it a portrait? Difficult questions, but I got help because suddenly everyone seemed to be interested in portrait photography!</p><p>The magazine Hollands Diep asked photographers to send in portraits for its annual photo contest. And <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.foammagazine.nl/index.php?pageId=3&amp;aid=21" target="_blank">Foam Magazine</a></font> published a complete issue on the idea of the photographic portrait. A perfect introduction to the solo exhibition in Foam of Richard Avedon, who made truly amazing portraits! Besides this exhibition you could visit solo presentations of portrait photographers all over the Netherlands in the first months of 2009, like Bert Nienhuis, Thomas Struth, Taco Anema and Otto Snoek. And although the Man Ray exhibition in The Hague Museum of Photography wasn't specially focussing on the portrait, it showed some beautiful examples to study. The portrait being popular already, <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.professionelefotografie.nl/meest-recente-uitgave/pf-nr2-2009" target="_blank">P/f Magazine</a></font> also published on the subject. And the Dutch association for professional photographers <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.gkf-fotografen.nl/" target="_blank">GKF</a></font> devoted a special evening to portrait photography with a debate. Etc, etc.</p><p>All this input inspired me a lot, but it didn't give me a straight answer to what a portrait truly is. Actually I only got irritated by the ones being convinced of answers like "absolutely facing the camera" or "absolutely not smiling". I think straight answers don't exist in this case and wouldn't it be boring to know exactly how to make a perfect portrait? I'm happy to continue exploring the subject myself, without looking for straight answers!
</p></description>
	<filters color="category-5" date="21.04.09" year="before"/>
	</item>

<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">New Website Online !!!</header>
	<image>images/10-04-09.jpg</image>
	<description><p>Welcome to my new website. I'm really proud to present this beautiful platform for my arts, photographic work and other activities. Please feel free to explore it all. I hope you will enjoy it as much as I do! Check regularly for new updates.</p><p>Designed by <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.paulswagerman.nl" target="_blank">Paul Swagerman</a></font>!
</p></description>
	<filters color="category-3" date="10.04.09" year="before"/>
	</item>

<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">Vrouw(en)kunst</header>
	<image>images/01-03-09.jpg</image>
	<description><p>I really had my doubts if I wanted to present my work at the debate <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.scheltemacomplex.nl/Programma/Vrouw_en_kunst_in_Scheltema" target="_blank">Vrouw(en)kunst</a></font> in Leiden. I was invited for the first presentation in a series of debates at Scheltema in Leiden about women artists and their (minor?) role at the artscene and -market. Personally I don't have any bad experience being a woman and not taken seriously because of this. But wouldn't it be interesting to show this non-experience? And it is always interesting to show some of your work! In the end it was a nice Sunday afternoon meeting with some women and one (!) man and mainly positive news for next generations.</p></description>
	<filters color="category-2" date="01.03.09" year="before"/>
	</item>

<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">Colors of Love</header>
	<image>images/12-02-09.jpg</image>
	<description><p>At the moment I'm working on a very interesting project called Colors of Love in <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.boijmans.nl" target="_blank">Museum Boijmans van Beuningen</a></font> in Rotterdam. Colors of Love is a workshop for second year high school students based on making combinations between images (paintings in the museum) and text (poems).</p><p>The whole project is in collaboration with the <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.skvr.nl" target="_blank">SKVR</a></font> and I was asked to develop and update the content of this workshop. Of course I'm also giving the workshops myself. Inviting young kids to enjoy paintings and poems is a very big challenge. But the theme that covers the entire workshop inspires everyone to create heart-warming results; LOVE!</p></description>
	<filters color="category-6" date="12.02.09" year="before"/>
	</item>

<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">Shown in Mama</header>
	<image>images/12-11-08.jpg</image>
	<description><p><font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.helmutsmits.nl" target="_blank">Helmut Smits</a></font> is an artist I use to photograph for. Mainly documentation of his exhibitions or artworks on location. But once he asked me to photograph  a concept he wanted to turn into a printed photograph being the piece of art itself. So he was the art director while I photographed "Two dead trees supporting a living tree". A very good example of his surprising and eye-opening artistic view on life.</p><p>Helmut decided to show this work in the group exhibition <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.showroommama.nl/projects/yes.cfm" target="_blank">"Yes"</a></font> in Showroom MAMA and that's how a very nice print of this photo ended up in the gallery I also use to photograph for!
</p></description>
	<filters color="category-1" date="12.11.08" year="before"/>
	</item>

<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">Perfect Combi</header>
	<image>images/24-09-08.jpg</image>
	<description><p>Studying Photography at the art academy AKI in Enschede I did an internship in 2003 at the studio of <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.erwinolaf.com" target="_blank">Erwin Olaf</a></font>. Doing my MA in Photographic Studies in Leiden I did an internship in 2005 at <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.fotomuseumdenhaag.nl" target="_blank">The Hague Museum of Photography</a></font>.</p><p>From 27 September 2008 until 18 January 2009 Erwin Olaf will show a solo exhibition at this museum. What a perfect combination for me! With my combined experiences and contacts I was asked to help at the day of designing the exhibition. Balancing and combining the enormous and beautiful prints of Erwin Olaf was a very interesting process to be part of and the result was amazing!
</p></description>
	<filters color="category-3" date="24.09.08" year="before"/>
	</item>
<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">I am a Guide</header>
	<image>images/26-08-08.jpg</image>
	<description><p>I started guiding people in the <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.boijmans.nl" target="_blank">Museum Boijmans Van Beuningen</a></font> for two reasons. The first was to achieve a better knowledge on the history of art. The second was to have a steady extra income besides my photography. But over the years I developed another third reason to not give up this job even though I don't need the money anymore. I really love guiding different groups in the museum from very young kids to old art loving lady's. Making them all enthusiastic in any exhibition in various ways is a big challenge. Besides that I enjoy the different reactions on art enormously!</p><p>The photo on the right is showing the pamphlet of the museums education programme 2008-2009 in which they published a photo of me.
</p></description>
	<filters color="category-6" date="26.08.08" year="before"/>
	</item>

<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">Online Expo</header>
	<image>images/02-08-08.jpg</image>
	<description><p>On the website of <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.nederlandsfotomuseum.nl" target="_blank">Het Nederlands Fotomuseum</a></font> you can discover parts of their collection photography. They created several online exhibitions of photographs that are part of their collection. I was asked to write a text to the online exhibition of Helena van der Kraan called "Diergaarde Blijdorp".</p><p>Visit the result using the following <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.nederlandsfotomuseum.nl/component/option,com_vitrine/Itemid,220/sub,detail/exposition_id,43/catid,0/lang,nl/" target="_blank">link</a></font>.
</p></description>
	<filters color="category-6" date="02.08.08" year="before"/>
	</item>

<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">Entry to Lexicon</header>
	<image>images/30-03-08.jpg</image>
	<description><p>My internship at <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.fotomuseumdenhaag.nl" target="_blank">The Hague Museum of Photography</a></font> in 2005 was mainly based on being an assistant in the production of the exhibition of Helena van der Kraan and working on her book that was published at the same time.</p><p>Because Helena also lives in Rotterdam and she's a very interesting artist and person, we continued to have contact afterwards. She was still looking for someone to write her entry to the "Lexicon of the History of Dutch Photography" and we decided me to try. It was a long process to end up with six pages on her work, four pages full of documentation and fourteen pages with beautiful photographs by Helena herself.</p></description>
	<filters color="category-6" date="30.03.08" year="before"/>
	</item>

<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">My Portrait</header>
	<image>images/05-02-08.jpg</image>
	<description><p>Being a photographer it's still flattering if another photographer decides to publish or expose a portrait of you. Two portraits of me made by Helena van der Kraan found a nice place in two books and an exhibition!</p><p>"Inspiratie Rotterdam" exhibition Het Schielandshuis in Rotterdam in 2007/2008</p><p>"Among Photographers" book published in 2007</p><p>"Helena van der Kraan" book published in 2005
</p></description>
	<filters color="category-5" date="05.02.08" year="before"/>
	</item>
<item>
	<header font="tradegothic" type="normal" size="12" color="111111">In a Lightbox</header>
	<image>images/23-01-08.jpg</image>
	<description><p>The shop where I usually go to print my photos, <font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.beeldgebouw.nl/" target="_blank">Het Beeldgebouw</a></font>, exhibits two of my artworks! One is shown in a lightbox, which fits perfectly to the image.
</p></description>
	<filters color="category-2" date="23.01.08" year="before"/>
	</item>

</agenda>


<over>

<item label="Information">
	<description><p>This website shows the work of Lotte Stekelenburg (1980).<br/>A selection of her photography is divided in three portfolios; Commissioned, Portrait and Self. In commission Lotte photographs mostly in the art and cultural scene and finds it challenging to work for clients with a strong view on visual aspects, like artists, musea, architects and performers. Besides taking a look at her photography, you can wander through her notes to get a better idea of all the activities she is up to within her discipline.</p><p>More information<br/><a href="http://www.lottestekelenburg.nl/cv-lotte-stekelenburg.pdf" target="_blank">download biography</a></p><p>Contact<br/>
<a href="mailto:post@lottestekelenburg.nl">post@lottestekelenburg.nl</a></p></description>
<font color="#000099"><a href="http://www.lottestekelenburg.nl/cv-lotte-stekelenburg.pdf" target="_blank">download biography</a></font>
<br/><br/>Contact
<font color="#000099"><a href="mailto:post@lottestekelenburg.nl">post@lottestekelenburg.nl</a></font>
</item>
</over>

</lotte_stekeleburg_config>